Guide to the Papers of Rev. Richards A. Zariņš, 1883-2008 M1938
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 2. Correspondence
  - Displaced persons in camps in Europe, 1947-1953
    - "U": Uhder, Ivar Erik; Uhder, Ruth; Ulpe, Bruno; Ulpe, Marija; Ungurs, Mirdza; Upenietis, A. (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - "V": Vagars, Melānija; Valdmeris, Miķelis; Vairogs, Elza; Vanags, Dzidra; Vaskis, Zelma; Veinbergs, Filips; Veits, Anna; Vējiņš, Arturs; Velberga, A.; Veperts, Ieva; Vidiņa, Selma; Vidiņš, Herberts; Vidmans, Nikolajs; Vīdners, K.; Viesis, Hedviga; Vilciņš, Andrejs; Vilciņš, Ansis; Vildavs, Olga; Vilde, Dzidra; Vilde, R.; Virs, Ernests; Virziņš, Alberts; Vistucis, Atvīds; Vītols, Alberts; Vītols, Olga; Voits, Alida; Volff, Ursula (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - "Z": Zaļaiskalns, Arvīds; Zālītis, A.; Zariņš, Arnolds; Zariņš, Arvīds; Zariņš, Eduards; Zariņš, Lidija; Zeberga, Zenta; Zeibots, Austra; Zeibarte, Lucija; Zeidenbergs, J.; Zemītis, Elvīra; Ziemelis, Bruno; Ziemelis, Ludmilla; Zilberts, P.; Zīverss, Oļģerts; Zubeckis, J.; Zutis, K.; Zutis, Z.; Zvagulis, Mirdza; Zvaigzne, Z.; Zvirbulis, Eduards; Zvirgzdiņš, Jānis (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Resettled Latvians in the USA, 1949-1954
    Feldmanis, Jūlijs, 1889-1953
    - "A"-"J": Aizsils, Helga; Alksnis, Alma; Alksnis A.; Amerika, Herta; Audermanis, Arturs; Austriņš, Kārlis; Auziņš, Augusts; "B": Bāliņš, Alberts; Baumanis, K.; Bernšteins, Jūlijs; Bērziņš, Marta; Birkāns, Jānis; Birzgalis, V.; Bogmanis, Ed.; Brizga, Ieva; "C": Čakste, A.; Cers, Alfons; "E": Elmuts, Voldemars; Eizenšmits, Arturs; "F": Fricsons, Juris; "H": Hofmanis, Aleksandrs; "G": Gailis, Ernests; Ginters, Margarita; Grīnbergs, Anna; Grinups, Zinaida; Grišjānis, K.; Grobers, O.; Grozgalvis, V.; Gudermanis, A.; Gulbis, Elsa; "H": Henkels, Ralfs; "I": Ierasts, V.; Ivans, Jānis; "J": Jakobsons, Arnolds; Jakobsons, K. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - "K"-"O": Kacens, Aleksandrs; Kadilis, O.; Kadilis, P.; Karbe, Rudolfs; Karlsons, Haralds; Kellijs, Arijs; Kļaviņš, Jānis; Kļaviņš, K., Klucis, Olga; Konrads, Silvija; Krastiņš, A.; Krolls, Otto; Krūmiņš, Milda; Kurmiņš, Ilga; "L": Lauce, Aina; Liberts, Jānis; Līcis, Eduards; Liepa, E.; Liepiņš, K.; Lietiņš, K.; Lola, U.; Lūks, Erna; "M": Maizīte, Erika; Mateus, Vilis; Mednis, Jānis; Morītis, Voldemārs; "N": Nīkurs, Zelma; Norītis, Gustavs; "O": Osis, Aleksandrs; Ozols, Alfreds Antons; Ozols, M.; Ozoliņš, Berta; Ozoliņš, Laimonis (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - "P"-"Z": Paipals, Fricis; Paozols, E.; Pēkšēns, Elizabete; Pelnis, Adolfs; Petersons, Voldemars; Porietis, Jānis; "R": Renbergs, Lidija; Renke, Anna; Robežnieks, K.; Rubenis, Alfreds; Rupeiko, Aleksandrs; Ruperts, Margarete; "S": Salovs, Katrine; Skudra, G.; Silenieks, Mārtiņš; Šmits, Julijs; Šterns, M.; Stērste, P.; Stivrins, K.; Štrauss, J.; Striķis, K.; Stulpiņš, Zelma; "T": Tenisons, A.; Tenisons, K.; Tone, Elma; Treimanis, Arijs; Treimanis, Jānis; Tracy, Vanda; "V": Vanaga, Erika; Viļumsone, Olga; "Z": Zaķis, R.; Zariņš, Kārlis Haralds; Ziemelis, Jānis; Zvēriņš, A.; Zubeckis, Jānis; Zundmanis, Alma (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1947-1948 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1949 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1950 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1951-1953 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1954 (Box 59, Folder 5)
  - Latvian pastors: correspondence and related materials
    - Āboliņš, Roberts, 1918-2002. Correspondence: 1952-1999 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Anševics, Arvids, 1902-1976. Corr.: 1963 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Baumanis, Fricis. Corr.: 1951 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Bergmanis, Edgars, 1904-1981. Corr.: 1949 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Bergman, J. Corr.: 1953-1954 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Bergs, Edgars, 1878-1961. Corr.: 1946-1961 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Bērziņš, Evalds. Corr.: 1950-1952 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Bērziņš, Ludis, 1870-1965. Corr.: 1948-1960 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Bērziņš, Ringolds. Corr.: 1957 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Bilzens, Kārlis, 1912-1993. Corr.: 1946-1982 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Birnbaums, Alberts, 1903-1991. Corr.: 1950-1953 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Birznieks, Kārlis Arnolds, 1903-1993. Corr.: 1947-1968 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Birznieks, Kārlis Arnolds, 1903-1993. Corr.: 1972-1982 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Brencis, P.; Corr.: 1962 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Briedis, Arturs, 1910-1986. Corr.: 1949-1953 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Briedis, Kārlis. Corr.: 1951-1957 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Brože, Ernests, 1898-1994. Corr.: 1949-1950 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Caune, Elmārs, 1915-1983. Corr.: 1950-1974 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Caune, Sarma. Corr.: 1999 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Cepure, Uldis, 1935-2005. Corr.: 1974-2000 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Cilnis, Jānis, 1907-1966. Corr.: 1982 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Čops, Adolfs, 1905- .Corr.: 1950-1987 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Čuibe, Leons, 1915-2010. Corr.: 1948 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Daugmanis, Jānis. Corr.: 1950 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Dombrovskis, Andrejs Fricis, 1882-1964. Corr.:1948-1959 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Dūmiņš, Arturs, 1911-1998. Corr.: 1947-1947 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Dzirnis, Jānis Alberts, 1911-2005; Corr.: 1949-1954 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Eglītis, Adolfs, 1899-1992. Corr.: 1948-1979 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Eglītis, Pēteris, 1884-1973. Corr.: 1949-1968 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Ernstsons, Jānis Arnolds, 1909-2000. Corr.: 1947-2000 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Fedders, B. Corr.: 1962 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Freimanis, Kārlis Herberts, 1908-1980. Corr.: 1947-1963 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Gabliks, Jānis, 1898-1955. Corr.: 1950-1954 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Gaide, Ivars, 1936- .Corr.: 1963-1967 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Galiņš, Alberts, 1899-1987. Corr.: 1950-1981 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Goba, A. Corr.: 1954 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Gobiņš, V. Corr.: 1979 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Graudiņš, Adolfs, 1904-1957. Corr.: 1949-1955 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Graudiņš, Jēkabs, 1896-1964. Corr.: 1947- (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Grauds, Didriķis, 1896-1980. Corr.: 1952-1960 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Grendze, Ilze. Corr.: 1999 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Grinbergs, Teodors, 1870-1962. Archbishop. Corr.: 1947-1962 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Grīnvalds, Vitauts, 1931-. Corr.: 1979 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Grīslis, Egils, 1928- .Corr.: 1958-1995 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Grīvāns, Hugo Maksimilians, 1901-1987 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Grosbach, Arnolds, 1909- 1979. Corr.: 1947-1979, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Gulbis, Alfreds, 1913-1977. Corr.: 1947-1955 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Gulbis, Alfreds, 1913-1977. Corr.:1957-1975 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Gulbis, Modris, 1927-2002. Corr.: 1962-1998 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Gulbis, Osvalds Rudolfs, 1910-1979. Corr.: 1949-1961 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Gulbis, Tālivaldis, 1920-1981. Corr.: 1967 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Hermanis, Kristaps, 1909-1980. Corr.: 1947-1968 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Isaks, Volrads, 1907-1968. Corr.: 1951-1965 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Jaunzemis, Pauls E., 1910-1982. Corr.: 1947-1982 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Jesifers, Herberts, 1915-1999. Corr.: 1947-1966 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Kampe, Leo, 1912-1975. Corr.: 1950-1966 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Kaupiņš, Alfreds, 1928-2004. Corr.: 1961 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Ķerģis, Eduards, 1914-1990. Corr.: 1947-1984 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Ķinēns, Jānis, 1914- Corr.: 1979 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Ķiploks, Edgars, 1907-1999. Corr.: 1945-1952 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Ķiploks, Edgars, 1907-1999. Corr.: 1953-1958 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Ķiploks, Edgars, 1907-1999. Corr.: 1967-1998 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Kiršfelds, Ansis, 1915-1980. Corr.: 1949-1963 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Ķirsons, Pauls, 1913-1965. Corr.: 1948-1963 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Kleinbergs, Oskars Davids, 1905-1988. Corr: 1947-1963 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Kleperis, Pēteris, 1904-1969. Corr.: 1963; 1970 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Kness-Kneznskis, Gustavs, 1903-2003; Corr.: 1952, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Kramiņš, Fridrichs, 1906-1998. Corr.: 1950-1953 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Kraulis, Oļģerts and Elizabete Corr.: 1947-1953 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Kristbergs, Fricis Traugots, 1945- Corr.: 1979 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Kristbergs, Zanis, 1913-1998. Corr.: 1949-1983 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Kronis, Kārlis, 1914-1986. Corr.: 1949-1985 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Kugrēns, Jēkabs, 1914-1965. Corr.: 1954-1963 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Ķullītis, Jēkabs, 1890-1957. Corr.: 1945-1957 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Kundziņš, Kārlis, 1883-1967. Archbishop. Corr.: 1948-1967 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Kušils, Harijs, 1912-1956; Corr.: 1950-1953 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Kuškevičs, Kārlis Tālivaldis,1925- .Corr.: 1980 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Lamberts, Eduards, 1908-1984. Corr.: 1949-1953 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Lange, Edgars Andrejs, 1907-1996. Corr.: 1950-1991 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Langins, Pēteris, 1911-2000. Corr.: 1946-1967 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Lappuķe, Edgars, 1914-1974. Corr.: 1947-1958 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Lazda, Jānis Vilpers, 1905-1987. Corr.: 1950-1966 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Lazdiņa-Zuševica, Lauma, 1954- .Corr.: 1979-1987 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Lezdkalns, Otto. Corr.: 1948-1954 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Liepiņš, Arnolds, 1908-1982. Corr.: 1947-1962 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Liepkalns, Arturs, 1921-2001. Corr.: 1995-1999 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Līventāls, Arturs, 1916-1989. Corr.: 1959-1962 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Lūsis, Arnolds, 1908-1993. Archbishop. Corr.: 1947-1985 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Mačs, Edmunds, 1904-1991. Corr.: 1948-1954 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Mačulāns, Ādams. Corr.: 1948-1950 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Mangulis, Arnolds, 1908-1978. Corr.: 1950-1954 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Matulis, Jānis, 1911-1985. Corr.: 1975 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Mednis, Jānis, 1922-2003/ Corr.: 1978 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Meisters, Jānis, 1909-1978. Corr.: 1948-1963 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Mekšs, Jēkabs, 1908-1999. Corr.: 1952-1961 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Mēters, A. Corr.: 1955 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Mežezers, Valdis, 1910-1982. Corr.: 1949-1957 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Mitulis, Aleksandrs, 1893-1985. Corr.: 1946-1963 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Mužiks, Ringolds,1914-2000. Corr.: 1947-1987 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Nesaule, Pēteris, 1907-1996. Corr.: 1950-1985 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Oliņš, Alfreds, 1911-. Corr.: 1974 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Osis, Jēkabs, 1894-1982. Corr.: 1950-1958 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Ozols, Alberts Georgs, 1915-2009. Corr.: 1949-1998 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Ozols, Jānis, 1876-1957. Corr.: 1949-1952 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Ozols, Nikolajs, 1910-1980. Corr.: 1947-1975 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Pavasars, Eduards, 1906-1975. Corr.: 1947-1966 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Piebalgs, Arturs, 1908-1992. Corr.: 1952-1975 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Podiņš, Carl, 1872-1952. Corr.: 1947-1949 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Prauliņš, Jānis, 1911-2001. Corr.: 1950 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Putniņš, Eduards, 1909-2008. Corr.: 1948-2000 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Rautenšilds, Arnolds Gustavs, 1906-2006. Corr.: 1951-1993 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Reinfelds, Nikolajs, 1914-2001. Corr.: 1963 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Reinfelds, Romans Reinholds, 1914-. Corr.: 1947-1982 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Reinsons, Arvids, 1902-1979. Corr.: 1953-1962 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Romans, Jānis, 1903-. Corr.: 1948-1958 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Roseneck, Vilhelm. Corr.: 1947 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Rozītis, Elmārs Valdemārs, 1909-1981. Corr.: 1947-1978 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Rozītis, Elmārs Ernsts. Archbishop. 1948-. Corr.: 1987- (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Rumpēters, Arkādijs, 1890-1962. Corr.: 1949-1962 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Ruperts, Fricis Herberts, 1912-1992. Corr.: 1953-1978 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Rūsa, Egons, 1909-1996. Corr.: 1953, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Sakārnis, Oskars, 1902-1978. Corr.: 1947-1977 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Saliņš, Laris, 1952-. Corr.: 1983-2000 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Sanders, Visvaldis, 1885-1979. Corr.: 1956-1969 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Sarkanbārdis, Ernests, 1908-1973. Corr.: 1949-1961 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Sautiņš, Kārlis, 1904-1958. Corr.: 1947-1954 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Šēfers, Viesturs, 1902-1978. Corr.: 1946-1967 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Selmers, Kārlis, 1892-1960. Corr.: 1946-1959 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Siebergs, Jēkabs, 1864-1964. Corr.: 1947-1953 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Siliņš, Jānis, 1908-1973. Corr.: 1946-1948 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Siliņš, Jānis, 1908-1973. Corr.: 1949-1950 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Siliņš, Jānis, 1908-1973. Corr.: 1951-1966 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Skrodelis, Alfreds, 1894-1983. Corr.: 1947-1956 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Slokenbergs, Roberts, 1898-1957. Corr.: 1946-1957 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Šmits, Edmunds Tālivaldis, 1902-1984. Corr.: 1947-1959 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Sniedze, Oļģerts P., 1932-. Corr.: 1998-1999 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Straumanis, Gustavs, 1909-1986. Corr.: 1951-1954 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Strautmanis, Voldemārs, 1893-1972 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Strautnieks, Jānis, 1906-1984. Corr.: 1959-1979 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Sudārs, Alfrēds, 1893-1980. Corr.: 1953-1966 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Teriņš, Jānis, 1893-1980. Corr.: 1947, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Treus, Armīns, 1901-2006. Corr.: 1959-1981 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Treus, Felikss, 1903-1958. Corr.: 1950-1958 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Turks, Jānis, 1906-1999. Corr.: 1950-1988 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Upīte, Zanis, 1908-1988. Corr.: 1961 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Urdze, Jāzeps, 1909–1985. Corr.: 1948-1949 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Valters, Kristaps, 1930-2003. Corr.: 1947-1991 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Vārsbergs, Vilis, 1929-2012. Corr. 1984-1999 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Vēdzele, Teodors, 1905-1982. Corr. 1961 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Vējiņš, Julius, 1902-1975. Corr.: 1950-1951 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Veinbergs, Aleksandrs, 1905-1991. Corr.: 1948-1980 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Vekmanis, Kārlis E., 1907-. Corr.: 1947-1966 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Voitkus, Arturs N., jun., 1911-1991. Corr.: 1948-1978 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Voitkus, Verners, 1911-1978. Corr.: 1952, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Zahlis,Wilhelm Otto, 1880-1961. Corr.: 1948 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Zemītis, Pēteris, 1904-1950. Corr.: 1950-1956 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Ziedonis, Arvids, 1931-. Corr. 1999 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Ziemiņs, Arvids, 1913-1898. Corr.: 1953-1963 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Zīraks, Teodors, 1902-2000. Corr.: 1950-1974 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Zvirbulis, Eduards, 1908-1988. Corr.: 1947-1988 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Zuzāns, Andrejs, 1888-1962. Resettlement documents.Corr.: 1949-1962 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Zuzāns, Andrejs, 1888-1962. Corr.: 1949-1962. Latvians in Senatobia, Mississippi. (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Leading clergymen of the United Lutheran Church of America, ULCA
    - Beck, Alfred L., 1917-1985. Corr.: 1960-1966 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Fry, Franklin Clark, 1900-1968. Corr.: 1952-1962 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Graefe, James A. Corr.: 1961-1984 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Henry, Karl S. Corr.: 1950-1951 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Hoyer, Conrad H. Corr.: 1950 (Box 17, Folder 2)
      Krumbholz, Clarence E., 1887-1956
    - Kirsch, Paul Andrew. Corr.: 1948-1957 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Knubel, Frederick Ritscher. Corr.: 1950-1955 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Kreider, Eugene C., 1899-1959. Corr.: 1949-1953 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - "B"-"W": Barnes, Roswell P. - Walinski, Frank Stephen (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Latvian diplomats in exile
    - Bīlmanis, Alfreds, 1887-1948. Corr.: 1946-1948 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Briedis, Valdemārs. Corr.: 1947-1957 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Dinbergs, Anatols, 1911-1993. Corr.: 1947-1961 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Feldmans, Jules, 1889-1993. Corr.: 1949-1953 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Grosvalds, Oļģerts, 1884-1962. Corr.: 1948-1955 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Šillers, Rūdolfs, 1896-1981. Corr.: 1946-1958 (Box 17, Folder 11)
      Lielnors, Harijs, 1900-1978; Zariņš, Kārlis Reinholds, 1879-1963
    - Spekke, Arnolds, 1887-1972. Corr.: 1954 -1960 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Zariņš, Kārlis Reingolds, 1879-1963. Corr.: 1948-1959 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Political letters
    - Political letters, 1949-1991 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Publishers and editors: correspondence and related materials
    - Āboliņš, Aleksandrs. Newspaper "Latvija",1948-1954 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Daņķens, Jānis. Publishing office "Grāmatnieki". Germany, 1948-1949 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Dobelis, Konrads. Newspaper "Brīvais Latvietis", 1949-1950 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Eglājs. Publishing office "Liesma". Germany, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Neilands, K. Publishing office "Litera". Germany, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Pomers, A. Monthly "Dzirkstele". Germany, 1949 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Raudzens, Pēteris. Latvian Lutheran Church publications. Germany, 1949 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Skrastiņš, Hugo, 1914-1999. Publishing office "Jaunais vārds". Germany, 1947-1950 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Eglītis, Andrejs, 1912-2006. Monthly "Ceļa Zīmes". Sweden, 1953-1954 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Freivalds, Osvalds. Latvian Lutheran Church publications. Sweden, 1950 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Pauzers, Z. Koge-Nord. Denmark, 1946-1948 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Švābe, Arveds, 1888-1959. Latvju Enciklopēdija. Sweden, 1952 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Rudzītis, Helmārs, 1903-2001. Newspaper "Laiks", 1949-1995 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Rabācs, Kārlis, 1902-1983. Newspaper "Laiks", 1949-1952 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Spilners Ilgvars, 1925-2006. Newspaper "Laiks", 1999 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Moora, Astra. Newspaper "Laiks", 1999-2000 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Bičole-Rumpētere, Baiba, 1931-. Newspaper "Laiks", 1999-2001 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Ķiploks, Edgars, 1907-1999. Publishing house "Sējējs", 1953-1959 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Ķiploks, Edgars, 1907-1999. Monthly "Ceļa Biedrs", 1960-1966 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Ķiploks, Edgars, 1907-1999. Publishing houses LELDAA, LELBA, 1973-1987 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Strautnieks, Artūrs. Monthly "Ceļa Biedrs", 1955-1967 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Voitkus, Arturs, 1911-1991. Monthly "Ceļa Biedrs", 1990 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Dobelis, Eduards, 1915-1977. Publishing house "Latvju Grāmata", 1949-1954 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Irbe, Viktors, 1922-2005. Newspaper "Latvija Amerikā", 1951-1988 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Jauntirāns, Juris. Children's magazine "Mazputniņš", 1965 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Purgailis, Kārlis, 1909- Monthly " Drauga Vēsts", 1946-1947 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Rumaks, Leons, 1919-1987. Rumak's Bookstore, 1969-1975 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Cimbulis, Gunārs " Universitas"- Valters, Kristaps "Ulubele" etc. (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Friends and contemporaries
    - "A": Āboliņš, Gunārs - Apkalns, Longins (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - "A": Andersons, Edgars (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - "A": Annuss, Augusts (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - "A": Akmentiņš, Osvalds, 1951-1995 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - "B": Balodis, Oļģerts - Bundža, Kārlis (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - "B": Bērziņš, Ivars (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - "B": Bokalders, Jānis, 1946-1965 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - "C"-"D": Celle, Māra - Dzirne, Aleksandrs (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - "E"-"F": Elks, George - Fricson, Vera (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - "F": Fogelmans, Zanis, 1948-1951 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - "G": Gailīte, Angelina - Gudaitis, Frank (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - "G": Grauds, Elza, 1946-1955 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - "H"-"J": Hazners, Vilis A. - Jordan, Irma (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - "K": Kalēja, Ida - Ķuzulis, Kārlis (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - "L": Labsvīrs, Jānis - Ļūļa, Aleksandrs (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - "M": Maikovskis, Bole - Muhlenbach, Olga (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - "N"-"O": Nagel, Jānis - Ottow, M. (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - "P": Paegle, Vaira - Puže, Lilija (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - "R": Rabačs, Elsa - Rūsis, Armīns (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - "S": Salenieks, Auguste - Stott, Victor (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - "S": Stange, Anna, 1947-1978 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - "T": Taivans, Leons - Truce, Austra (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - "T": Tobis, Sandra, 1959-1999 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - "U"-"V": Upītis, Pēteris - Vītols, Annija (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - "Z": Zadovs, Juris - Zutis, Arveds. Unidentified (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Cards
    - Thank you letters and cards, 1949-1980 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Postcards (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Greeting cards: Christmas, Easter, Birthday etc., 1947- (Box 20, Folder 10)
- Series 3. Collected correspondence of contemporaries
  - Lenow, John (Liepa, Jānis), 1891-1965. Corr.: 1935-1962 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    John Lenow was an activist of Latvian cultural and social life in New York since 1920-ties. The head of the New York Latvian Society from 1935 to 1946. The correspondence contains letters to and from the leaders of Latvian Society in New York.
  - Rabācs, Kārlis, 1902-1983. Corr.: 1949-1970. "A"- "K". (Box 21, Folder 2)
    Kārlis Rabācs was an editor of the newspaper "Laiks" from 1949-1970. The correspondence contains letters he received from well known Latvian emigre writers, poets, authors, literary critics, etc.
  - Rabācs, Kārlis, 1902-1983. Corr.: 1949-1970. "M"-"Z", unidentified (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Rev. Gulbis, Osvalds R. correspondence with Stiebriņa, M., 1955-1958 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Correspondence between Mrs. M. Stiebriņa and unidentified person
- Series 4. Speeches and writings
  - Sermons and related materials
    - Sermons and related materials, 1947-1951 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Sermons and related materials, 1951-1952 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Sermons and related materials, 1952-1953 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Sermons and related materials, 1954 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Sermons. Bible lessons, 1953-1955 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Sermons and related materials, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1957 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1959 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1960 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1961 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1962 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1963 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Pastor's work journal, 1947-1963: leaflets, related materials, chronology and topics of sermons (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1964 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1965 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Materials for sermons, 1966 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1967 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Materials for sermons, 1968 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Sermons and related materials,1969 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Sermons, 1970-1971 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1973: January-April (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1973: April-June (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Sermons and related materials. Pastor's work journal, 1973: June-August (Box 27, Folder 1)